[Music]
he
uh
[Music]
hello good evening good day everybody
and welcome back to the ask abijit show
it's been a while since we did this this
is going to be the final episode of the
year it's been quite a year and we have
quite a year coming up ahead as well so
I hope you're all doing very well and in
the coming year 2024 there's going to be
a lot more of these interactive live
streams the askab show we're going to do
a lot more of these and we're going to
have a lot of possibly impromptu live
streams as well so we'll see about that
now let's see who all is there on the
live chat let's see who all is there I
can see bye-bye SG Indo Arian harid
bador Lone Ranger melwin really now
geopolitical Dubai have a nice day Rahul
guruin Guru Vishnu Kura Zed Zan Sami
bahti T Meg harprit Singh shut takur pan
Kumar Singh base strictly South Africa
South
African San paniker vnav Ajay Kumar
akula vanika pidar Deepak Singh rajput
Forum kacha G K Joseph Stalin shiv Singh
RoR monish Sabin
praj toan CH
Anushka angamali nikil volcano Manish
Chri sidhant banot kumal chinmai Martian
thread Ripper Bodhi yes indeed Su pan
Shashank hi ragi Aman wakil shakar
Yasir Akash dikshit Shiva Singh
paniker Dylan T sham adikari s boria
hello PS really now Rahul
chinmai who else Kenneth tan from the
Philippines hello sir technical adviser
salmon Souza Guru Vishnu uh shubam Dylan
Shani Messi SG Raj Bora Dr J Shankar
Supremacy hello hello sir hello
ma'am Vian vun Awan melwin and and lots
of people Sayan thread Ripper jine Raj
sing okay I'm going to stop greeting
everybody RTI J Raju ran na
nabanita okay let me stop greeting
everybody that's what I'll do all day so
okay uh I won't be able to greet all of
you individually but you have my
greetings and thank you so much for
being on this live stream I really
appreciate your viewership and your
support so with that said let's get into
the questions I can see Raj tra as well
after yeah good to see you so let's get
into questions let's get into questions
you have questions you ask me now and I
will start taking those
questions all right let's see let's see
let's take this question okay
geopolitics there's a lot happening
right now there's a lot happening in the
Middle East there's a lot happening
elsewhere as well Lone Ranger says what
do you think our response should be
regarding the houti attacks look it's
something that does affect us right the
houti attacks uh okay so that we
understand what's happening we go to the
map the map is our best friend so
where's the map let's find the map here
is the
map one second let's put that on the
screen here we have it uh let me bring
it to a different place so that it's
yeah here we go so this is the map now
we're talking about the houti attacks
right so where where is this happening
so it's happening in at the intersection
of the Red Sea in the Gulf of a
this is a choke point called the
straight of bab Al mandb okay there are
these very important choke points that
are extremely critical in geopolitics
I'll tell you what these are one is the
straight of Gibralter you see this choke
point here between the uh Atlantic Ocean
and the Mediterranean Sea that's an
important choke point then you have the
Su Canal it's a very narrow Canal so
that's another choke point then you have
the straight of bab al- mandab here okay
between the Gulf of Adan and the Red Sea
there's the the the straight of hormos
between the Sea of sashtra and the
Persian Gulf and then you have the
straight over here the straight of
malaka these are the most important
vital critical geopolitical choke points
because you you you do something over
here you choke off traffic shipping
traffic over here you're going to bring
much of the global economy to a halt
okay so what what's happening is that
the houis the Anar Allah faction of in
Yemen who have been at the receiving end
of for a decade and a half of a you know
a war that is primarily done by Saudi
Arabia on the behalf of the US right and
also by the US so they have been
fighting these forces for a decade and a
half and I have a very interesting
podcast on this channel a podcast with
Dr Isa blumi which goes into detail
about the situation in Yemen and what's
what's been happening there right so the
ansar Allah faction who are based most
likely in southern Yemen they are uh
they have decided to choke off this this
uh straight the straight of bab almand
what's here you go bab Al mandb straight
and they have missiles they have drones
they have attacked Israeli ships they
have attacked possibly other ships as
well possibly I'm not sure Israeli ships
definitely and they have said that they
will only allow Russian sh ships to
Transit through this place through the
straight and this is an extremely
important straight because much of the
traffic that goes travels between East
and West passes through this straight
and then it goes through the sus Canal
so if you choke off this straight Egypt
is going to take a huge hit because much
of their economy depends on the sus
canal and the global economy will take a
huge hit so then ships you know
container ships Transportation ships
cargo ships will be forced to go all the
way around the the Cape of Good Hope
like in the ancient days and that's
going to increase costs and it's going
to increase costs everywhere so that's
the deal so that's what's happening
that's what the yemeni houis are doing
they have choked off this tra of Babel
Mand and the US has sent a task force a
couple of uh aircraft carrier uh task
forces they've sent uh to to bring the
situation back to normal but let's see
how that goes as as of today it's still
a work in progress and right now the the
huis are successfully choking off this
straight so the question is what about
us what should we do about this look uh
it does affect us in India okay uh much
of the shipping much of let's talk about
oil okay every nation depends on energy
and we are buying uh oil from various
sources including Russia and much of
this Russian oil that we are acquiring
comes through this straight of babal
Mand but if it comes to Russian ships
it's going to be fine because the
yemenese the houis won't block W you
know Target those ships if it comes
through other ships then the the houis
could Target them so it could affect our
uh energy Supply right oil supply all so
that that's that's a problem we could
face and if that happens prices could
eventually go up to a certain extent in
India prices of normal regular
Commodities right because oil
Powers transportation and transportation
it affects the price of Commodities
tomatoes onions and whatnot right
standard stuff so it could affect us
right uh so that's a deal so what should
we do look uh even though it does affect
us and it has the potential to affect us
uh this is not our fight from India's
perspective we have to be very clear
this is not our fight we should
encourage the sides both the sides
whatever sides are involved in this to
come to uh you know some kind of
understanding some kind of agreement
some kind of resolution on the
negotiating table over a meal over a few
drinks if they want to instead of
fighting it out we should encourage them
to do that but we should not get
involved directly in this matter because
it's not our fight it's between um it's
between the west and the yemenis the
yemenis the the huis the they have been
at the receiving end for for a long time
I'm I said a decade and a half it
actually goes back to the 1970s 1980s
even before that so uh this is an an
Anti-Imperialist uh Force the Anar Allah
faction in in Yemen and they are
fighting the west and they are uh
showing what they can do and obviously
they have they are supported by Iran
they have Iran's support and it's not
just verbal support like we we in India
we love verbal support oh somebody said
something nice to me and this support
that's not support they have material
support most likely from
Iran so that's the deal so I would say
that we should from India's perspective
we should encourage both the sides all
the sides to come to a peaceful uh
agreement some and a cessation of
hostilities but we should not get
involved directly in this matter at all
even the Chinese are involved and
they're sitting there and and watching
things happen they have a few ships in
this region they have uh the Chinese
have a naval base in jibou okay I I've
shown this in the past where the Naval
Base is located I'll not do that again
because it will take too much time but
there are a few Chinese ships also
deployed warships that are deployed in
this region and they have ignored
distress calls from ships that have been
hit by the hoties so uh the Chinese are
are essentially just sitting and
watching and they're enjoying what's
happening because it kind of helps them
so that's the deal right now so my
simple point is India should not get
involved directly in this matter we
should encourage all sides to negotiate
maybe facilitate negotiations if
possible but not more than that because
it's not our fight all right okay let's
take a different
question we took
that uh byby says is D dead look I have
no idea there are reports of all kinds
that come out in the media uh that that
the the terrorist D was uh poisoned
apparently by by some with someone uh
but there's no official word on it
because you know his whereabouts have
been Pro he probably has been residing
in Karachi but you know there's no
photograph of him that's come out for
the past 20 30 years so there's been
this very tight uh clamp down on any
information that comes out regarding
this particular terrorist okay who is
sheltered and harbored by Pakistan uh in
the past there's been speculation that
the isi had bumped him off bumped him
off because he was becoming a li or
whatever right so we don't know is it it
is it not I I personally obviously only
have access to information that's in the
public domain I don't have any access to
classified information so I can only say
that I do not know maybe may not but uh
that's the situation
right
um volano says why is the American
education system better than the Indian
education system look today the American
education system is going down backwards
it's it's going to the dogs okay look at
what's happening in Harvard the dean or
whatever she that lady is of Harvard she
has been caught
red-handed plagiarizing and she she has
this long history of plagiarizing going
back to her student days and and yet
Harvard is brising it out and saying
that what she has done is right and
there's nothing wrong with it and let
then it's it sets a president that
allows students to do the same thing and
claim president that look you exonerated
this lady for exactly the same thing so
you cannot now accuse me of plagiarism
so everybody is going to preze now so
and and we know what's happening in the
US the education system
is it is the root cause of this epidemic
of wokeism that's uh that's rampaging
through the US right uh the education
institutions have been taken over by the
leftist and all but look at it
historically the education system in the
US was the probably the best in the
world because they had standards they
had high standards look I I have done
three episodes of the ask ofion show
about the education system what what is
wrong with our education system uh I
think it's episodes 28 30 32 somewhere
around that somewhere around that
episode number okay check it out I've
gone into it in great detail the
education system in India is is horrific
okay what it does is
that think about what happened to Shas
ranuan The education system nearly
destroyed him he was a genius level
mathematician one in a 100 years kind of
mathematician and the education system
me he they failed him in in what in
English and and some other subjects and
he used to get top marks full marks in
math but he used to fail everything else
and that's why they said that he was
good for nothing they should there and
that that was the collodial education
system before 1947 and what do you think
we have today we have the same education
system nothing has changed so the
education system in India is designed to
turn out clerks and peons it's designed
to convert bright intelligent curious
young children really intelligent young
children into zombies it's designed to
turn them into clerks and peons it's not
designed to turn out leaders it's not
designed to you know uh help the student
rise to the fullest extent of his or her
potential the education system excels at
seeking out in destroying talent and
rewarding mediocrity okay uh and in the
education system in India it
treats the
staff okay the employees the teachers
and and the academic and non-academic
staff as the true stakeholders and the
students as simply Expendable Canen F
the purpose of an education system is to
treat the student as a stakeholder not
the teacher the teacher's job is to
bring out the best in the student and
prepare the student for eventually
becoming a bright young confident
adult who can go and and take Take On
The World and change the world okay and
serve the country and society and we do
the opposite of that so the US education
system was better Geared for that I mean
we have so many fake subjects and fake
courses in in in
India if you have a
degree in Home Science if you have a
degree in gender studies in women
studies what are you going to produce
after you get the get your degree if I
have an degree let's say in Engineering
in mechanical engineering Computer
Engineering whatever I know what I can
produce you can produce something
tangible for society once you have a
degree in Humanities some Humanity or
whatever what are you going to produce
for society if there's this very popular
uh degree right English literature so
many kids and go and take this score
this degree in English literature what
are you going to produce after that what
are you going to produce for society the
education system is is still nothing
nothing has changed it's still the 19th
century colonial British education
system we haven't changed anything and
we have this NEP and all that let me go
not go too deep into that okay which
does reach really does nothing it
doesn't really change
anything okay so so that's the thing
we're going to need drastic deep reforms
in the education system to turn it for
to to convert it into a much better
system okay it's going to hurt the
so-called stakeholders who are the the
academic and non-academic staff who have
not performed anything for for for a
century and a half what simply rent
seeking and leeching of the system of
the country of the
society uh so theep major changes are
needed and we are nowhere to towards we
have we have not taken any steps towards
even beginning that process in my
opinion and yeah that's my opinion
despite everything that
um whatever has come out in the in the
public about the new education policy or
whatever it it does nothing it doesn't
really solve the real issues the core
issues so yeah the education system in
the US is actually designed to prod
produce uh bright young adults who can
really contribute to society it's not
based on writing long essays once a year
in your exam it's not about passing
exams it's about learning actual skills
and and using the skills to contribute
something valuable to society and the
Indian education system is the opposite
of that so that's the deal
and we need to change something about
it uh Aman wakil says please tell us
about the naval mut how did India go to
India what happened look there are like
three different questions I have spoken
in depth about the Indian um the the
naval rebellion of 1946 I have a couple
of videos on this channel just go to the
channel search for 1946 or or Naval
Mutiny or Naval rebellion and you find
at least two three videos on my channnel
in which I have gone into this in depth
okay so I will not go answer this in
depth here because I have done that just
just search for it on this channel and
you'll find your answer what happened to
subash Chandra BOS watch my podcast with
anua I've got how many three podcasts th
far with him on this channel uh look
most likely I I am of the opinion that
and I agree with anoj that most likely
the the person known as Gnam Baba was
most likely subash Chandra BOS and he
lived till 1985 most likely and to
understand why he was in living in
anonymity and all that you need to watch
the podcast because it's a long uh it's
it's a complex topic right so
yeah geopolitical dub says French
president in and Biden out how do I see
it look the Americans have been trying
to pressurize and squeeze India more and
more the pressure is incre increasing on
India and it's all geared at disrupting
and influencing the 2024 general
elections in India okay
uh they the Americans would like to have
to see a weak government come to power
in 2024 in India and not the strong
government of Prime Minister Modi right
they would like a weak coalition
government to come in India so that they
can then control India there are lots of
assets that they have within India let's
just put it that way I'm I'm not going
to take names or anything if you
understand you understand what's what
what do they say if you know you know so
they have many assets within India at
various uh levels let's say okay without
being specific or naming naming anyone
so they would like those assets to
become more prominent and to have a more
prominent role in India's future right
now that's impossible because of the
incredible popularity of Prime Minister
Modi they are trying to pressurize India
and create all kinds of trouble for
India so Mr Biden had been invited he
had agreed and that's why it was
announced that's why India announced it
and then you know what theyve accused
India of of of targeting Terror American
US citizen terrorists on American soil
terrorists who want to blow up India's
Parliament and and blow up a India
planes you know that panu guy uh good
good what whatever G panu that fellow
who was a dual citizen of the US in
Canada he is a terrorist
who is a US citizen and who is acting
who is
actively uh working to harm India and
the US shelters this guy all right and
they have accused India of uh
allegedly uh attempting to assassinate
murder this this take out this guy on us
soil they have produced no evidence
obviously they have made several
statements and made accusations but
there's no evidence that's been
forthcoming and as a result of this and
and you also have the hardip Singh Nar
thing in Canada and all uh So based on
this they they have said that India has
done crossed a certain line what about
kasum suani what about AMA Bin Laden who
the US assassinated Pakistani soil what
about kasum suani who they assassinated
on Iraqi soil when someone acts against
the US the US can kill that person
anywhere they even killed their own
citizen Anar Al AI in Yemen a US citizen
and his young son his teenage son both
US citizens the Americans did that so
the Americans for them rules are
different for the rest of the world the
rules are different even if this is true
I'm not saying it's true this allegation
that India targeted this panu fellow
right so that's why the you the world
doesn't respect the us anymore because
it's a hypocritical double standards
State they have a certain set of
standards and rules for themselves and
the rest of the world has to Simply obey
their dictat there's no rule of law
anymore the so-called rules-based World
Order is fiction okay so and and they
would like to pressurize India more and
you know what's happening in India's Far
East in Manipur uh I have I have a whole
episode about that okay uh so that's
that there's that the Manipur situation
it's a geopolitical thing okay it's
nothing to do half of Manipur at least
half of Manipur is under foreign
occupation right now and the reason why
we are not doing anything about this is
that
this may not be the right time and this
the these foreign occupiers of half of
Manipur uh well look at what they are
seeking okay a separate nation in Christ
they're fighting three nations Burma
they're not even burmes by the way those
those terrorists who are on manipuri
soil who are squatting on manipuri
territory Indian Territory are not even
burmes they don't even speak the burmes
language or practice burmes Culture by
the way they are from Yan and China by
the way okay but so it's a complex thing
so there's the Manipur issue Manipur is
is in great pain right now then there's
Kashmir and there's new infiltration
coming in from Pakistan from Pakistan
occupied Kashmir and recently aim Monir
or whatever the name is of the new of
the of the current Pakistani Chief of
Staff army army boss he was just just
last this week perhaps I think he was in
the US and he met what's his name
blinkin and he met Victoria Newland you
know if you know about if you know who
she is you know wherever she goes chaos
ensues so that's the deal with the US so
Mr Biden tried to the US whoever
controls Biden because Biden is well
he's demented he's no longer capable of
taking care of himself let let alone run
a country so whoever is is behind the
The Throne whoever is truly controlling
the power in the US have decided to pull
out Biden so as to humiliate India Okay
but well and so
so India went ahead and invited m m and
he accepted because I'll tell you
something the French are the only nation
within NATO okay who have a somewhat
independent semi Ki independent foreign
policy and let me tell you a secret they
do not see the us as an ally or a friend
okay uh they they would like nothing
more than to break free of uh us
hegemony for France is the only nation
in Europe that
has uh quasi independent foreign policy
and they have a great amount of
convergence of interests with India and
they are realistic and pragmatic they
are the one nation in Europe that has
most more or less refrain from pointing
fingers at India and lecturing India
about various things that the US and
Germany Etc lecture India about and
another nation in Europe that is these
days uh becoming uh more aligned with
India is Itali Madame milone is a is is
the leader who is spearheading that so
it's great that M Mak has decided has
accepted India's invitation and he will
uh Grace India's Republic Day uh
celebrations it's uh it's going to be uh
it's going to be something that uh
further enhances India France ties the
relationship India will remember what
the US has done and India will remember
that France stepped in and and and was a
was willing to you know graciously step
in and uh help India out so this all
these things are going to have long-term
consequences okay long-term means it's
going to matter even 20 years down the
line one thing we know about India is
that the Indian people are an extremely
emotional people and Indians don't
forget Indians forget many things but
certain things they don't forget and
this is one of the things that India
will not forget so here we are so I
think it's a great thing for the India
France relationship all
right anurag says who is next to she in
China is there any chance that there are
pro-indian leaders in the CCP nope nope
nope nope nope nope there may be some
certain moderate leaders Etc uh pro-
India everyone's Pro China in the CCP
okay you simply can't be you have to you
have to prioritize your own nation's
interest only you will only be Pro
another Nation if that is convergent
with your nation's interest that is the
simple rule of of of real real politic
of geopolitics National interest First
Nation
first uh now who's next to she ah we
don't know the Chinese system is so
opaque and uh and Mr Xi Jinping is so
paranoid that nobody would dare to
position himself or herself as number
two and there's no herself there because
all the leaders in shining's Inner
Circle are men so so yeah it's it's
dangerous for a leader to portray
himself or herself as a number two Fen
ping so we don't know who's next in
China okay as long as shining holds on
to holds on to power there'll be no
number two and once whatever for
whatever reason he's no longer in power
whenever that happens there could be a
power struggle and there could be some
kind of yeah chaos possibly in China for
some time at least uh so yeah that's a
deal and I don't think there are any
pro-india leaders in the Chinese
Communist party that's where we are
okay
um let us see other
questions
[Music]
um this is by apma early Christian era
killing lots of women in millions what
might take well yeah that's recorded
history that's that's
um that's history that's not really
emphasized in the west they don't like
to emphasize that but it's
true look 1500 years ago
the culture in
Europe was a local
manifestation of the culture in India
they the same Gods with the same
polytheistic culture with different
names so in various parts of Europe we
had different manifestations different
local manifestations of this ancient
Indo-European polytheistic culture let's
go back to the map where's the map
here's the map let's
go so here's the map now now look here
let me
yeah so in the Slavic regions you had a
different set of
divinities in in Greece you had a
different set of divinities which
includes Anatolia today turkey uh in
Italy you had a different set of
divinities in France the goic area in in
in present day Spain in in the British
is and the Nordic regions you had a
different set of gods but these were all
the same Gods different manifestations
of the same divinities for example we
have the god Indra in India which is who
is the let's say the head of the chief
of the rigc pantheon of gods Indra is
known to
have um two weapons the vajra which is
the Thunderbolt And The Hammer which is
also called the vajra right and the the
god Zeus in in Greece has the same
attributes the god Jupiter in Rome has
had the same attributes the god Thor in
in Scandinavia had the same attributes
the god perun in in the Slavic parts of
the world had the same attributes it's
so it's all the same thing right so
Christianity was imposed upon Europe by
force let's understand this very clearly
it was not something that was accepted
by the Europeans willingly it was
imposed by force and the original
culture was smashed out of Europe
forcefully okay there was the northern
Crusades and whatnot it's and read
what's the what's the name of the book
The darkening age you go to Greece today
you go to Greece today or go go to Rome
and you will see that all the old
temples of the old gods of the true gods
are smashed if you look at the the
statues the idols of those gods Apollo
Nike uh Aras whatever these are all
smashed the noses are broken the arms
and legs and other body parts have been
smashed out right so this was a
violent process okay and then we know
very clearly in India at least that
women have a very exalted role in Indian
Society at least historically it's been
that way the past Thousand Years the
taint of foreign culture came into India
and women had to hide in their houses
and hide under the wheel uh the wheel we
wheel okay let's not go into that so
before before 1000
ad the status of soci women and Society
in India was totally different from what
it is today women had very prominent
roles in society they were respected
probably more than most men so that's
deal and you had the same in
Europe okay you had the same in Europe
before Christianity came in and women
were the healers women were the doctors
women were they played very important
roles in society so all this ancient
knowledge of of Herbal Healing and
whatnot which we Call Aura here and
which may have its which may have had
its counterparts in Europe all of that
was was the domain of of women okay and
that was very important role that women
played in society and to smash the old
culture out the status of women had to
be
degraded so any woman who had this
ancient knowledge was then termed as a
witch okay you have any ancient
knowledge any knowledge that that a man
would not have then you're going to be
branded as a witch you're going to be
burned at the steak and this happened
over centuries there was this big witch
burning Spate in the Middle Ages the
Dark Ages in Europe a few centuries ago
like I don't remember exactly when the
second most popular book at at one point
in time in Europe was the malus malarum
the Hammer of the witches which was a
manual on how to identify which is and
how to destroy them how to to kill them
how to torture them to extract
confessions and so on the second most
popular book in Europe was written by
two Christian priests two Christian
priests malus
malarum okay and so there was this reign
of terror so many women and some men
also was were accused of being witches
and burned alive and this persecution
went for centuries to enforce obedience
blind obedience and fear in society this
is an entire culture based on fear the
Europeans don't they have lost their
original culture they have lost their
original culture it's been smashed out
of them by force and they don't they
don't even know about this
I say this on occasion right that India
is is a society that suffers from PTSD
as well as Amnesia PTSD is
post-traumatic stress disorder well
Europe also has gone through that and
they have no
recollection excuse me of their pre
Christian culture there is there are
some movements here and there to to uh
revive that um I forget asatu is that
religion in Scandinavia that they're
trying to revive which uh you know uh
hearkens back to the old polytheistic
religion and there is a Slavic
revivalism as well paganism a little bit
of that here and there people are trying
and if you go to Lithuania laia Etc
there is some Slavic Revival there and
they don't have priests to offici
officiate the the traditions because the
rituals so they
often they often invite Indian Vic
priests to do that for them well what
does it tell you it's the same culture
it used to be the same culture so to
destroy this culture they they you know
brutalized the society in Europe they
destroyed all the temples they destroyed
the great Tree yrail in in Scandinavia
the tree the the Tree of Life uh and so
on so it was a brutal brutal violent
process and like you say millions of
women were murdered just for having
ancient
knowledge there
okay okay let's take some more
questions Dada says will the voke
culture get into India like the US and
Destroy Indian family families by
increasing single mothers and other
forms of non-marital relationships
between couples couples also lgbtq IIA
plus zerm whatever that is it's it's a
big threat it's a big threat woke
culture okay I believe in diversity but
what form of diversity do I believe in I
think the world is a beautiful place
because of diversity you go you travel
to different parts of the world you you
every new place you go to you encounter
a new culture a new way of life a
different culture a different way of
life and different traditions and
different people and that's what makes
the world beautiful the diversity I go
to Vietnam this this beautiful local
culture local Cuisine local Traditions
wonderful to see I go to Indonesia a
whole different set of you know naans
culture way of life I go to uh China
various parts of China it's different I
go to Japan they have their own
beautiful way of preserving their
ancient culture i i i let's say I go to
various parts of Africa I go to various
parts of Europe Europe is a kind of a
monoculture unfortunately because of
what we just went into but you go to
different parts of the world you find
different cultures different Traditions
different ways of life that's what makes
the world beautiful the diversity now
when youy to force fit all this
diversity into one place where that
doesn't belong that's when you're going
to have
trouble that actually creates
monocultures by force fitting diversity
into a small country or wherever and
that's what the West is trying to do
they call it diversity but they're
trying to actually impose a monoculture
okay and uh one of the best ways to do
it is to destroy the fabric of society
by destroying whatever people believe in
by so that's what's happening in the in
the west most people are rejecting
Christianity and they're becoming
atheists and once you give up your
ancient Traditions even though it was an
imposed tradition okay the old actual
culture of Europe like I said is the old
Indo European culture which was smashed
out of existence but whatever moral
framework they've had for the past
Thousand Years the Europeans is the
moral framework of Christianity it is
better to
have any moral culture than to have
moral set of guidelines and to have no
moral guidelines at
all so today because of people rejecting
Christianity for a variety of good
reasons I would say assume so because
they've rejected that they have no set
of moral guidelines anymore to live by
and then it's easy to to infect them
with this woke uh mind virus like Gad
like Professor gadad would say the Mind
virus the woke mind virus so and if you
look at us society today I mean single
parents are the norm most kids grow up
in the care or so-called care of their
mothers who are single mothers most kids
don't have a father figure in their life
and you know lots of Studies have shown
that if if a kid grows up in a single
parent family but that parent is a
father that kid has a very low mean much
lesser chance of becoming a delinquent
of of going to jail and being criminal
but if that same kid grows up in a
single parent family that that has a
mother instead of Father there's a very
high chance of that kid going down the
wrong path in life that's just fact okay
many Studies have shed this so in the US
most kids are raised by
mothers and you see what's going on in
the US crime is rampant homelessness is
rampant drug use everyone does drugs
everybody does drugs in the US it's it's
us culture now it's American
culture and now I don't know J Z genz is
the kids born after a certain whatever
year I don't know 2019 whatever it is I
think 30 or 40% of gen Z identify as
lgbtq plus whatever the Spectrum thing
is right I mean
what and now they're trying to export
that nonsense all of that assorted
nonsense the whole package to other
countries and the great uh
uh Advantage the US has is that they
control
entertainment okay everyone watches
Hollywood everyone watches us Cinema us
uh series you know those OT series
whatever you want to call it and and
it's it's full of that what's that new
Game of Thrones thing the rings of power
or whatever it was I mean I have not
watched the single episode but I've read
the reviews everyone complains of the
same thing they have totally destroyed
the story and they've tried to woke vfy
everything and make everything
diverse so entertainment today in the US
is about lecturing the audience instead
of entertaining them entertainment used
to be about escapism that okay I'm going
to watch this movie maybe it's a
two-hour movie for two hours I'll forget
my life and I'm going to escape into a
different world a different universe and
today if you watch any movie you're not
able to escape anything because they're
going to lecture you they're going to
lecture you about the voke agenda
the message the message that they have
to to you know impart so that's what
Disney is doing that's what everyone is
doing so and Indian kids they watch all
this crap they watch all this stuff okay
and that's coming into the the Mind
space of Indian kids today look at
Indian teenagers they are also doing all
kinds of nonsense like
uh uh premarital relationships like like
have 15 different partners in five years
that sort of thing and uh all that so
that mind virus is already coming into
India okay and if it succeeds in in
taking root in India it's going to
destroy Indian Society it's going to
destroy Indian society and it's going to
be
terrible okay so yeah it's it's
something we as a society have to be
very we first of all have to be
cognizant of the threat this poses we
have to be aware we have to accept the
fact that it has already appeared in
India this this problem and we have have
to take the right steps to combat this
because this is something that is aimed
at destroying Indian society and
destroying Indian culture this is
something that's an
outgrowth of uh the Marxist neo-marxist
ideology of DEA and fuk the French
so-called alleged
philosophers who uh who then uh became
very influential in the West
and that's what the American
academics uh you know that took it forth
from the 1950 60s onwards and now that's
all that's taught in the US universities
and all so yeah I think it's a huge
threat and India needs to be cognizant
of this and India needs to take measures
against
this all right let's see something
else your kab says what's your
perspective about being an atheist and
being a rationalist and the difference
between these two terms I don't know
what's okay an atheist person is a
person who doesn't believe believe in
God okay no God a
rationalist is also most likely an
atheist and the rationalist they they
think about everything
logically um so uh what's a rationalist
somebody who uh regards who views the
entire world from the perspective of
facts and logic and in scientific
explanations so that's there's nothing
wrong with that that's a good thing
that's a good way of looking in the
world look why does why do things happen
they happen because of the laws of
nature and because of human psychology
when things happen in nature it's
because of the laws of physics and the
laws of chemistry and biology are also
consequences of the laws of physics okay
so if something happens in nature it's
because of the laws of physics and not
because of anything else as far as we
know that's the best evidence that we
have and when something happens in
society is because of the the forces
that that shape human history
geopolitics power human psychology and
so on so you have to look at things
rationally nothing wrong with that now
the problem with certain so-called
rationalists is that they make fun of
people who believe in God and people who
are spiritual or religious and all that
I mean
be it's it's perfectly good to be an
atheist it's your choice don't believe
it's perfectly good it's actually great
to be a rationalist look at everything
rationally and logically but uh today
the people who identifies as rationalist
are the ones who will denigrate certain
cultures and not other cultures and they
will you know do a token criticism of
certain cultures once or twice and then
they will use that as the as the as the
basis to the claim that they they are
they criticize everybody equally uh so
from the proper definition of the term
rationalist is a person who looks at the
world through logic and through the laws
of science if they know science I'm not
sure if all rational know science but
they talk about science for sure so I am
also a rationalist for sure I look at
the world from the perspective of logic
cause and effect okay
causality uh that's fine but it doesn't
mean that I have to also be an
atheist right the world is complicated
doesn't mean that I have to be an
atheist to be a rationalist uh look we
understand next to nothing about the
universe we understand we are able to
see observe less than 5% of the universe
less than 5% of the everything we see in
the universe whatever we is visible to
us whatever is measurable is less than
5% of what's out there in the universe
95% of the universe is dark it's
invisible to us and that 5% that we see
we don't even understand that properly
so our understanding of the laws of
nature is minim to say the least and to
use that as the basis of your entire
understanding of the world and to
criticize others who have may have a
different path or different Viewpoint
perspective I think it's a little bit
too much I would say okay so that's how
I see the world the the thing is this
so I this is not I'm not this is not an
observation about all so-called
rationalists I don't really know many of
them but see truth is that the less you
know the more certain you are about your
convictions and beliefs the less you
know the more you think you know
everything and the more you know the
more you realize that we know actually
know nothing about the world next to
nothing about the world so that's my
perspective okay I do see the world
rationally from that perspective I'm a
rationalist but I don't have to be an
atheist to be a rationalist and yeah
that's all I'll
say okay
uh kid ryes says I've seen your podcast
on Mr Gandhi I'm assuming is Mr mandas
Gandhi okay if these things are factual
then why don't people or the Elite Class
of our country accept it
look whatever I say you can fact check
it if these things are factual what kind
of statement is that why don't you go
ahead and fact check it all the
information is available in the public
domain
sir you can without being a his Ian
without being a scientist or whatever
you can fact check everything I say all
the information is available in the
public domain just
do you know how to do a Google search go
and fact check it and then if I am wrong
you show the proof very
simple so these things whatever I've
said are factual they are based in
nothing but facts reality historical
records okay so why don't don't people
why don't most of the people in our
country accept it it's because of the
education education
system the education system in
India teaches people to
memorize what is written in the
so-called
textbooks it teaches people to
obediently accept what authority figures
tell
them and the education
system fails to teach
the kids rational
thinking critical thinking critical
thinking is something the education
system doesn't teach our people so our
people don't know how to think they
don't know how to fact check so then
they simply hero worship because of the
because you have been taught to
obediently obey everything your teacher
says for 15 20 years so it just becomes
ingrained in you you become conditioned
like sheep so our education system
produces generation after generation
after generation of sheep obedient sheep
who will simply obey okay so whatever
so-called great historian or so-called
great writer says we're going to believe
oh yes he said this so it must be true
oh everyone says so and so historical
figure is a God so we're going to
worship that person that's it is that's
what it is people simply don't think
people simply don't cross check what's
written in the textbooks and people are
taught that whatever is in in the
textbooks is infallible that is it you
don't need to know anything beyond
that that's another thing the education
system does it says all you have to
study is what's written in the textbook
you don't look beyond the textbook
that's all you don't do any
extracurricularly reading you don't read
other books we're going to burden you so
we're going to overburden you so much
with our textbooks with our homework
that you simply don't have the mental
capacity the mental bandwidth to read
anything extra and so you will see no
other perspective
so that's why most people in our country
they simply blindly like sheep accept
the official narrative and when it comes
to the Elite Class well that's a whole
different story let me not go into that
I think you can
think all
right let us
see abijit K says should research
institutes like the Indian Institute of
science be taken out of the Ministry of
Education in favor of Department of
science and technology or something Al
like look I would say that certain U
research institutes especially should be
given full autonomy look and and you
know um I have a pod I have two podcasts
with Professor goam Desi Raju he is a
very senior uh scientist chemist India's
foremost chemist and he uh works at the
Indian Institute of Science and I have
one podcast in which we actually walk
around the The Institute Institute and
we
but he he explains the history and all
that about the Institute very
interesting podcast I would recommend
you watch it uh and he did
allude on camera and maybe at some other
time also at the fact that the the
nonacademic people the bureaucrats who
Who Run The Institute they are a little
bit too controlling and they and this is
something that is not limited to the I
it's it's it happens across the board so
typically in the Indian education system
in higher in all institutions including
higher education uh the budget and all
decisions are controlled by non-academic
people that is bureaucrats career
bureaucrats who don't really even
understand education actually some of
them may some of a few May a few May I'm
not saying all are bad but most of them
are simply disinterested and they just
want to control things because you know
it gives them the sense of power most of
them not all of them right so look at
something like Princeton
where uh The Institute of whatever it
was at Princeton where Einstein
Oppenheimer and all they spent a
significant portion of their careers
that's a place where you can do whatever
you want obviously you have to
be you have to be worthy of being
accepted into the Institute obviously
only the best of the best
were accepted in in
Princeton but then they could do
whatever they wanted and sometimes it
works uh to the benefit of science
sometimes it it kind of takes over the
urgency from scientists so I think there
should be some kind of Balan system and
you know too much bureaucracy and too
much uh political Etc uh paternalism is
actually bad for research U one of the
best models for doing research that has
a tangible impact on the world is the US
institution called
DARPA which was founded in the same year
that drdo in India was founded and look
at the Divergent
trajectory that both institutions have
taken DARPA produces such incredible
technology okay or much of it is
classified and what they do is that they
hire scientists they they they identify
scientists in the US academic system in
the US universities Etc who are working
on interesting and useful Technologies
and they give them Grant like proper
funding not like peanuts funding here
and there proper Mega funding and they
give them two years or let's say two
years okay they give them a certain
amount of time sometimes it's one year
sometimes it's two maybe sometimes it's
three let's say it's two years they give
them this am x amount of money they give
them a time frame you have two years in
which to take this money utilize it to
bring your research to a food full
completion and if it doesn't work no
issues that's a risk we are willing to
take so it's not like if if the result
if the research isn't completed then
there's going to be a black black mark
against the scientist no in science
certain things don't work out and that's
what you have to also understand so
DARPA has a great model it has what how
many employees 150 employees that's it
it's a flat thing and uh and lots of
scientists work under DARPA but they are
they work independently okay their lives
are not controlled by the bureaucrats in
DARPA Dara doesn't have bureaucrats so
that's how it is so that's a great model
I think we the model of that we use in
India is this ancient archaic 19th
century British colonial Education
System model that is applied everywhere
including to the best institutes IC is
actually one of the best institutes in
India the best the best scientific
Institute for scientific research in
India uh so yeah that's the thing we it
would be great if we can create uh give
more autonomy to institutes like IC and
it would be great if you could create
something like DARPA as well uh but
DARPA in indan DARPA would need to be
able to fund scientists who are doing
great work in India and the problem in
India is that in most of the
universities there no there's no real
research that's
happening the scientists are only
so-called scientists scient you know
you're not a scientist unless you're
doing some active research and trying to
solve a problem that hasn't been solved
before that's research not recycling the
same old nuclear nuclear configuration I
took this nucleus and I default to this
extent and now I have some new new
characteristics that I'll publish a
paper on what a waste of
time okay most of India's nuclear
scientists that's what they
do so that's the problem in India once
you have a job in the academic system
it's a job for life and then you just
pretend to do something that's what most
of them do not all there are some
genuinely great scientists Bright Young
scientists as well in India no doubt
about it okay across the Indian academic
system maybe in various universities
maybe in the iits definitely the iisc
but most of them I would say are
mediocre and good for
nothing facts are facts so yeah it this
all needs to be
reformed we we there's this crying need
for reform but yeah nothing is happening
thus
far all right
okay today we have a lot of questions
about education Shak sakam Chri says
what should be the ideal education
system and how should the in government
implemented without having any
propaganda by opposition or other in
intellectuals first of all the education
system has to be about Merit only Merit
not reservations and if you're going to
do reservations you should do
reservations not based on your so-called
cast but it should be based on your
financial
status kids from poor familyes should be
given Financial uh you know Financial
support and that's all but once you once
someone is given financial support then
they have the money and then their
academic performance should be the only
yard stick by which you you uh you know
progress in the academic system and in
life so reservations are a huge huge
huge problem that's destroying the
Indian education system first of all
because if I if if there's a kid who is
part of the so what's it called General
category then they have to get way
higher marks than a kid in various
Reserve categories to get get a seat in
various institutions I IMS or whatever
it is you know nits and universities
it's it's horrible that's why everyone
wants to leave this country because they
feel that this country doesn't value
them they feel that this country gives
them a raw deal you know it's not the
Indian Society that's doing this it's
the Indian system that's doing it the
society is laboring under the system and
right now because of various political
reasons it may not be possible to to
abolish this thing called reservations
so that's where we are right so number
one you need Merit in the education
system and then the education system
should not go on for 20 years 25
years I think most people don't want a
master's degree they simply want to
start working at the earliest they find
something interesting some people like
cars find cars interesting so they want
to learn how to make cars or repair cars
or modify cars or whatever some people
like computers some people like building
big structures like Bridges and Roads
everybody wants to create something to
contribute something to society you
don't need to wait till 25 to do that
you you know most of us want to start
working at a young age why can't we have
a system in which you are taught the
basic stuff of life life like basic
history Communication in your native
language and Mathematics which is
important arithmetic not algebra
trigonometry you don't use that in real
life so teach the basic fundamentals by
the age of 13 14 and by 15 you can send
the kid as an apprentice with with a
salary with certain conditions you know
and it's only a few people who need
master's degrees in all that so the
entire system is geared towards the
wrong things and they understand that
the purpose of the education system is
to create Bright Young confident and
capable and highly skilled young
citizens who can go out into the world
with confidence and contribute
positively to society that's what's
needed the education system does the
exact opposite it creates these confused
non
non-confident young adults who don't
know what to do in life they are sheep
they don't know how to think they don't
know they don't have the ability to do
to do critical thinking that's what the
education system does in a country which
has that sort of a horrific education
system actually is
boomed so that's where we are today and
you know it's going to be difficult for
the Indian government to change this
entrenched system
because there are so many vested
interests it's going to be really hard
to do that but it has to be done so you
you're going to need Supreme leadership
to be able to do this let's see how it
goes right now we have some reforms that
are being done apparently NEP and all
that doesn't Inspire any confidence in
me at
least all right all right all right
education we have spoken about
that okay this is a question I get every
time like 15 times a day in the comments
and all that is India T planning to take
back Po and C Chinese occupied Kish do
you think it's ever possible it's
possible it will happen but we're going
to have to be
patient P see Pakistan like I always say
is a temporary Nation it's going to
disintegrate when the time is right it's
going to disintegrate by itself the best
way to win a
war is
by is is without having to fire a single
shot you achieve all your objectives
without having to fire a single shot and
without losing a single man that's the
best way to win a war wait patiently and
create the right conditions for the
temporary Nation to disintegrate on its
own there are a lot of internal forces
within Pakistan that will make it
disintegrate when the time is right
maybe 5 years maybe 2 years maybe 10
years maybe 20 years I don't see
Pakistan existing more than 20 years
down the line as as the way it is right
now and when it disintegrates po
obviously will reintegrate with India
what about C it'll take longer perhaps
okay but you never know so it's going to
happen it's going to happen but we need
to be
patient you don't want to start a
kinetic War you don't want to unless you
are you know that Victory is
inevitable and even if Victory is in is
in inevitable do you want to suffer so
and so amount of damage in the process
of Victory why not achieve Victory
without suffering any damage at all so
wait be patient India is growing India
is rising if we play our cards right and
if we ensure that we are not embroiled
in any major military Conflict for the
next 20 years India is going to surpass
the
China by the end of the century India
may even surpass the US by the end of
the Cent Cy but it's a long-term game
understand that we are not a nation that
was born yesterday okay the nation was
born in 1947 it was created in in this
form is a nation state in 1947 but we
are the world's oldest
civilization and for us 100 years is
nothing it's like yesterday A Thousand
Years is for us is a day is day before
yesterday so we have to think from that
perspective and we have to all
contribute in our own way to toward
doing that so p c all that will come
back in due time right now let's try
let's let's focus on making India more
powerful and stronger the economy the
infrastructure the education
system
entrepreneurship military and so on let
us all contribute in our own way and
that will set the process in motion it's
already in motion which will eventually
bring all these lost territories back to
India all right see we have lost a lot
of territory I've got to the map over
here I'm looking there let me put it on
the screen we know what territories we
have lost is historically what used to
be India I mean bat right bat was this
entire region from the Himalayas to the
the oceans and uh you know in 1935 the
burmes had voted to not partition
themselves from India the burmes wanted
to remain a part of India they had voted
in favor of remaining part of India and
yet it was parti so the British have
broken India into pieces so you know
when when chingis Khan in the year
1299 uh after his his conquest of quasm
when he he came to India chasing
jalaludin the coward what was the border
between India and and Central Asia it
was a pass in
Tajikistan so the border of Tajikistan
was the border between central Asia and
India in 1299 when chingis Khan came
pursuing jalaludin the coward and he
obviously eventually defeated jalaludin
in the battle of the indas in Punjab and
then he returned back to Mongolia
without ever setting foot crossing the
river the Great River so we have lost a
lot it's going to take time to recover
our ancestral
territories maybe it may not happen all
of it may not happen in our lifetime so
what our
descendants will regain that and that's
what we have to work towards so it's
it's a long-term process it's not going
to happen in our all of it may not
happen in our lifetimes maybe it will
but let's see all
right okay okay St crocodile says pram
when China attacks Taiwan and if the US
defends Taiwan militarily what response
should bat have in if the US doesn't
defend Taiwan what it may end up doing
look we don't know when if when or if
China will
uh March upon Taiwan militarily I mean a
military Invasion uh they have been
wargaming various scenarios we know what
Taiwan is I hope yes here's the island
of Taiwan this one here and you can see
um I'm sorry the map isn't on the screen
here's the map okay so we know where
India is so let's Orient ourselves go
eastwards and here we have
Taiwan okay over here so the Chinese
have been wargaming various uh scenarios
by which they can invade Taiwan and
recapture Taiwan they consider Taiwan to
be a renegade Province Taiwan is a
heavily defended Fortress of an island
and it
is an ally of the us obviously the US
has a vested interest in not allowing
Taiwan to go into Chinese hands so let's
consider this hypothetical scenario that
in year so and so maybe sometime in the
future near future let's say imagine
let's imagine hypothetically the Chinese
invade Taiwan okay then it's going to be
a big big hot War Taiwan is not easy to
conquer Taiwan has tremendous defenses
they are supplied by the US they have
the latest weapons and all that and the
Americans will do their best to not
allow China to take Ian without heavy
damage okay but let's say that the
Americans uh fail and the Chinese take
Taiwan okay so the scenario is that
China invades Taiwan so what should
India do in that situation well I would
say that India should make sure that we
secure the Maldives and Sri Lanka I'm
I'm saying secure not invade I'm not
suggesting that we should invade and
Conquer Maldives and Sri Lanka I'm
saying we should secure cure maldiv and
Sri Lanka and possibly Nepal as well it
will depend on the strength of the
Indian armed forces the Indian military
strength at that time whenever this
hypothetical Invasion happens and so on
right uh so yeah so if the Chinese take
such a step then India should also take
certain steps to safeguard its uh
National and civilizational interests
that's what I would say but it will all
depend on a variety of factors including
the strength of the Indian military and
so on and so so
forth FES says why were Islamic Invaders
not why were they unable to loot and
plunder India like the British the
British made India poor in just 150
years but the Islamic Invaders couldn't
do the same thing in 1,000 years look
the Islamic Invaders the Turks did not
rule India for A Thousand Years first of
all let's understand that okay the
process of invasion starts around 700
something ad with the invasion of Bin
kasum Muhammad bin kasum in in Sy
sometime in the 8th Century which which
was a temporary Affair okay and then the
turkic invasions start a few maybe two
centuries later so the process begins in
the 8th century and they tried and they
tried and they tried to invade India
they they first took Afghanistan
Afghanistan was the first Kashmir okay
Afghanistan is the original Kashmir
today you don't have a single Hindu or
Buddhist there it was a completely Hindu
Buddhist territory of India gandar so
this process
begins about a thousand years ago and it
took them 3 400 years to finally
establish a so-called Empire in New
Delhi and so you had the Delhi sultanate
which ruled certain parts of Northern
India for some time then you had the
so-called mugal Empire which was the
turky
Empire which uh was established in the
15th 16th century okay look up history
don't I don't remember dates I never
remember dates because it keeps my mind
free for other things for thinking so
you can look up the dates
and then the mul empire fell in the
1700s so they were in power for what 2
250 years that's
it okay and then you had various
sultanat in the southern part of India
and you had Bengal which was ruined and
today we have Bangladesh and so
on so they did not rule India for A
Thousand Years first of all and when the
mul Empire the so-called mul Empire was
it was at its peak theyed to send
tremendous amounts of Indian wealth to
Mecca Madina and to Central Asia and the
amount of the number of Indian people
they enslaved and send to the slave
bazars of Central Asia is beyond number
this is uncountable there are so many
people in Central Asia and in the Arabic
world who look very Indian why is that
you ask me because their matal lineages
will be Indian okay and I'm sure you can
imagine how that happened uh so they did
a lot of damage to India the the
so-called mugal the Turks and if you
look at the Indian GDP okay I I don't
have the graph right now with me the
Angus medison graph of the past 2,000
years so the decline in the Indian GDP
begins when the so-called mugal had
started ruling India and they had
captured large parts of Indian Territory
all right and there's a significant drop
in Indian population as
well so they did a lot of damage to
India but the British they elevated this
to the next level they did I don't know
hundreds of artificial famines in India
in 150 200 years okay they devastated
India because if you are starving how
will you fight so they killed off I
would say between 100 to 200 million
Indians through artificial famines and
they took plunder and theft to the next
level nobody can match the anglos in
thievery in Theft okay the biggest
nation of Thieves
ever is through uh so they they took it
to the next level the anglos the the
British
so clearly they were better than the the
Turks in in stealing and thievery and in
genocide as well so yeah they had a very
systematic way of extracting all the
wealth and resources and everything out
of India they built Railways for that
they built ports for that all the
railways all the ports all the
institutions they built were part of the
infrastructure of extraction it's not
some gift they gave to India it was
their infrastructure they built for
extracting everything of value out of
India and when the finally left India
they did of their own vition not because
somebody forced them them through
non-violent means they left because
there was nothing else left to plunder
from India everything of value had been
sucked out of India by that time so all
the wealth that India built up over
thousands of years it's all in the west
today all of it and the West the the
Western way of life and
and whatever wealth they enjoy it's it's
been redistributed through complex
methods across the West so yeah there
you
go all
right okay again
education why does the government spend
only 0.66% of GDP on R&D on two to 3% on
education will it increase in the future
and why doesn't the Indian government
promote R&D well that's a question for
the Indian government to answer okay I
do not know uh we defin L look the
education system is the key to the
future of of the nation of the
civilization so it really really really
needs to be reformed but maybe right now
it's a it's it's too much I don't know I
don't know what the reason is maybe it's
it's too difficult a task task right now
maybe there it's it's politically too
inconvenient maybe it's politically too
uh you're GNA come up with a huge amount
of
uh
opposition look you the government does
anything good to to benefit the nation
there's a huge amount of opposition to
India to the to the to the move you have
the farm laws and then there were these
horrible protests against the farm laws
and the Prime Minister took those laws
back okay even though there was no no
need for that but probably he did the
right thing at the time because all of
these most of these much of these
protests and all that resistance is
organized and fermented from outside of
India okay now if the let's say the
government goes ahead and and does some
genuine educational reforms something as
simple as detoxifying the Indian
textbooks history textbooks you do that
the whole leftist ecosystem will be up
in arms the entire anti-national
ecosystem will be up in arms and you
going to have a Spate of Articles and op
EDS published in the west accusing India
the government of India of being fascist
and trying to saffron ISE things and
trying to uh you know further hatred or
whatever whatever they allege okay and
that's going to that's maybe a problem
they don't want to take on right now
maybe I'm just assuming right so u i but
R&D well you know to have good
R&D you need good quality researchers we
have some very bright young people this
country and we have some bright senior
scientists as well but I would say that
the vast majority of the Indian
academics are mediocre and they are good
for nothing the vast majority there are
lots of Exceptions there are some really
bright people as well really good people
really talented and dedicated people as
well but the vast majority are
mediocre go to any Indian University and
see what just ask yourself how do I feel
in this
environment yeah so
so so if you increase the
R&D percentage of
GDP or the education percentage of GDP
it's going to get wasted at this point
in time the first step is to reform the
system and then you increase the
funding that's what needs to happen you
have a rotten system if you fund it more
it's going to get even more rotten that
is the problem that is the problem uh so
R&D I mean tell me which Indian
University let's talk about physics and
engineering and technology in which
Indian University is some great research
happening okay IIs there is some good
research op there Indian Institute of
science apart from the Indian Institute
of science tell me one Indian University
or IIT where some new groundbreaking
research has been done in the past 20
years please name
one no one's doing anything so what's
the point of funding them you first need
to reform the system get get rid of the
non-performers non-performers bring in
bright new Young talent and then fund
them that's the the process that's a
that's the chronological step-by-step
way in which this must be done and
that's
why that's why we have this otherwise
it's going to be completely wastage of
money total wastage of money all
right all right all right all right all
right right let's see what else ffff
says why has the US for its European
vasal to accept millions of refugees
from North Africa in the Middle East and
destroyed their demography but not its
other vasal like Japan and South
Korea there is some demographic change
happening in Japan as well by the
way okay they are being made to accept
certain flavors of immigrants right
now without naming anything South Korea
South Korea has lost its
culture the majority of South Koreans
are either atheist or Christians where's
the South Korean culture left in South
Korea de deracinated rootless youngsters
in South Korea that's what you have and
North Korea is a communist atheist
Nation So Korea has
been destroyed you know
culturally culture is gone how many
practicing Buddhists do you still have
in Korea in South
Korea so that's what's been done to
Korea so once
you you know eras a nation's culture you
can control it in any way you want
especially when you bring in your
culture bring in this Western culture
Western religions into the into the
nation that's how you can you know what
one of the biggest National Security
threats is cultural and demographic
change so that's what they do they
engineer this in Japan maybe the process
is beginning right now when it comes to
Europe yeah I mean look at the videos
that you that come up on social media
recently in Spain a whole Army of young
military age African males running
across the border or whatever it was in
you know uh infiltrating into into Spain
it was a
young large number maybe more than a
thousand of young military age males
African males why is this being done you
know the situation in France you know
the situation in Germany you know the
situation in the Nordic countries Sweden
Denmark Norway all that uh
Italy I
mean what's what is being done right now
in front of our eyes is that these
nations are being
destroyed and it's going to be
impossible unless there is it's going to
be almost impossible to to deport all of
these infiltrators because
they they're going to be made to
integrate in some way within Society
without without actually assimilating
they're going to impose their
culture uh so that's what's being done
that's what's being done to the US vasal
in Europe like you say you're correct
and the objective is to destroy European
Society that's what it is I mean
demographic change is a national
security threat it destroys Nations it
destroys culture demographic change is a
threat to any nation's sovereignty to
its culture to its cultural continuity
into its demographic continuity why
should a nation not preserve its culture
and its demography why
not why this forced so-called diversity
if they want to do it in the US do it
why are you forcing it on other nations
that's what they can do I have always
said this that there are only two major
powers in
Europe one is Russia the other is the US
and every nation in Western Europe is
dominated
by the US okay so that's what we are
seeing and what we know what's been
happening in Germany and all it's a
disaster so these nations are being made
to essentially commit harakiri that's
what's being
done um byby says M Mr emuel mcon of
France is very left yes he's a leftist
yes and he also allows migration so how
can he be respected by
Modi excuse me what I don't care what he
does in his
country I only care whether his
interests align with my
interests I will respect anybody who
align whose interests align with mine
and who will wa who will work with me
towards strengthening my nation while
also strengthening his Nation or his
interests I don't care what he does in
his country that's his problem that's
his business I don't understand this
this perspective that he does this he
does that I don't care what he does as
long as his interests align with mine
and he works with me which helps me I'm
going to respect him I'm going to
embrace him I'm going to hug him I'm
going to cherish
him what kind of perspective is this
this is the emotional perspective of
Indians Indians are so incredibly
emotional they don't see the world
through a realistic
lens I don't care what it does look at
the Americans they prop up these various
dictators in Africa what do the
dictators do in Africa horrible things
the Americans don't
care that's how geopolitics works it's
called real politic have you ever heard
of vishnugupta chanakya this is the
nation of vishnugupta chanakya and we
see the such
comments I don't care what he does in
France he's good for India so I'm going
to respect him uh it's not about respect
Baba it is not about respect it's about
National
interest it's not about respect it's
about National
interest if someone's in National
interest aligns with my national
interest he's good for me or she is good
for me and I'm going to work with
them what else does matter does matter
in the world what else matters France is
all the way there they have interest in
the Indian Ocean region which align with
our interests and they have another
interest in and you know they want to
break free of the US in some shape or
form eventually sometime in the future
that also is good for us and they're
willing to
sell good technology to India it's it's
a transactional thing sell buy and sell
okay but other nations won't even sell
so that's good for India so how do I
care whether he's left or right or green
or pink or blue I don't care whether he
allows migration and is's being forced
by the US to destroy his country I don't
care he's good for me I can work with
him look at the world from that
perspective from a realistic perspective
instead of looking at what religion they
are or what what ideology they believe
in or not believe in or what they do in
their country who
cares this is what I don't understand
about Indians that's what the education
system has done to Indians Indians don't
are incapable of critical thinking even
though Indians are the most intelligent
people in the world so strange that's
what the education system has done to
Indians think of the world from a
realistic perspective and ask questions
question all your assumptions first of
all first of all start questioning
yourself start questioning your
assumptions then you'll be able to
think uh what about China's next
probable nuclear test says guep no idea
look I have no idea what's happening in
China China is a black box opaque okay
very little news comes out from China
it's very tightly controlled so I don't
know we'll see if they do do it I can't
speculate without any actual data I
don't have data so I can't
speculate all right
right a good question Zed Zion says why
are the skians classified as Iranians
instead of Indo
Arians who does this classifications ask
yourself this question who does this
classifications whose classifications
are we currently accepting as the
standard narrative it's Western
historians everything has been created
by the
West all these narratives all these
so-called accepted uh mainstream
narratives and all that all of that has
been created by the West so the skians
are classified as Iranians the skians
well the best way to put it across as
Indo Iranians but Iran itself was this
tiny entity compared to India
geographically large but population
population density wise very sparse the
Persians themselves are are off shoot of
Indians okay who went Westward from
India and settled down let's put the map
on the screen in case people don't know
what Persia is I'm sure some people
don't which I don't blame you for okay
so Persia is Iran today's Iran and
historically Afghanistan Pakistan was
India right so India and Persia were
neighboring
uh you know political
entities Iran was a DOTA civilization of
India Iran the modern name is Iran which
has existed for less than a century the
actual C correct name is Persia the
people of Persia were the par people the
par rig Clan of the rig rig with Indians
okay and they settled down in they went
westwards out of India and they settled
down in this region and their Capital
was parur which is now called pipis
because we have to use Greek names
instead of indigenous names so the
Greeks called that city perspolis today
the Persians call it parsa historically
it was called parur is that not an
Indian name par Port the city of the par
people so that's the deal so even the
Iranians
are nothing today okay today's Iranians
are genetically somewhat different okay
because in the last two3 years there's
been a huge turkic influx into Iran and
they brought in lots of immigrants from
the Caucasus region so today you will
find lots of Iranians not lots but some
Iranians who have blue eyes and blonde
hair some of them may even have red hair
some of them a few of them okay that's
not the original Iranian look the or
origal Iranian appearance was light
brown skin brown eyes and dark hair that
was what the original Iranian person
looked like right
uh so the skians were another branch of
out of India migrants who ruled Central
Asia for a couple of thousand years at
least
and eventually they rein they re-entered
India as through an invasion about 2,000
years ago about 2,000 years ago and that
Invasion brought an end to the indog
Greek rule in Northwestern India in
gandhar and uh yeah in
Punjab so the keans re-entered India as
Invaders they were actually fleeing the
skan they were actually fleeing the
kushans who were fleeing the Huns long
domino effect over
here and then they established Kingdoms
in northern and western India some of
the mahak chatas ruled in sashtra in in
Gujarat and they were as Indian as
anybody else even though they had come
from Central Asia because they their
ancestry was Indian anyway so they left
India thousands of years ago they ruled
Central Asia for a long long time and
then they re-entered India and
reassimilated into Indian
society and their culture was more or
less the same as Indian culture the
skians were known to be sun worshippers
sashtra what does it
mean the nation of of the Sun s rashtra
solar nation sashtra which is the
Peninsular region of
Gujarat so the skians were genetically
more or less the same as Indians and
some
genetic uh traits picked up here and
there which is bound to happen when you
are nomadic Confederation that rules a
very large area but more or less they
were Indian there was no cultural Clash
when the skians invaded and and
conquered parts of India and started
ruling over India the mahak chatas in
Western India they were the protectors
and Servants of the great J langa Temple
of of sna right until the 6th 7th
Century
ad and then a different Dynasty comes
over that's a different story so the so
this classification of skians as
Iranians is a is a western invention
okay uh they say that the skan language
is is an Iranian
language so that's simply a western
classification we in India we simply
blindly copy what the West says and this
applies to Indian academics as well who
themselves are not capable of critical
thinking they'll simply copy what the
West says and that's why we are taught
that the skians are Iranians they're
actually Indo Iranians or Indo Arians
which is correct which is correct like
like X Zion says zed zed Zion says here
here all right who else what else
Gish says what's the current status
current status of the Russia Ukraine war
what's the current status the current
status is that there's not much
happening it's what's called slow War
the the past year if you look at the the
the lines on the map from between the
Russian the territories are conquered by
Russia and the territory is still in
zelinsky's so called
Power You Don't See Much movement the
boundaries are more or less static right
now there's some movement here and there
a little bit here and there there's a
lot of fighting
happening and now the ukrainians are
forced
to to enlist middle-aged men men in
their 40s and 50s even 60s that's the
new crop of of recruits into the
Ukrainian Armed Forces even women are
now being recruited conscripted to fight
in the war pregnant women so that tells
you everything you need to know they
have no youngsters
left the the flower of Ukrainian Society
the youngsters are dead males men
dead this entire thing has been a giant
meat grinder for Ukraine it has
destroyed Ukraine forever essentially no
men left no young men left even the old
men are being sent to to fight fight the
Russians are perfectly fine with that
they have made it a point not to destroy
Ukraine cities they have not done what
the Americans would do in a war flatten
entire cities they have not touched the
cities there's been some here and there
but overall the there are there are you
will see so much so many videos on
social media of you cre in women
partying in KB and whatnot does it look
like a nation at War the Russians have
made sure they don't they don't do that
okay so that's the situation the
Ukrainian war is lost from the Western
from the Western perspective okay it's a
proxy war between the west and Russia
and Russia has succeeded and they're
going to be patient they're going to
wait another two years if they need to
but eventually they're going to get
their way I have said this since
February
22 The Invasion the Russian special
military operation ordered by Mr Putin
began on February
2224 in the year 2022 and I said Russia
will win and for the longest time people
were saying Russia is losing Russia has
lost everything Russia has lost all its
men Russia has lost all there's no more
weapons left excuse me what's going on
right now everyone who was saying that
the West will win that Ukraine will win
where are where where are those people
today I have said it from the day one
that Russia is going to win this war and
now even the funding seems to have dried
up the Americans were sending I don't
know tens of billions of dollar you know
on ongoing basis to Ukraine that has
stopped now it's over
it when it is officially over depends to
remains to be seen maybe maybe in 24
maybe in 25 maybe in 26 Putin is patient
he's going to get his way and Ukraine is
finished this person zilinsky has
destroyed Ukraine as a nation okay
ukraina the Borderlands of Russia the
Slavic people that's what the nation
means what the name Ukraine means it
means Borderlands whose Borderlands
Russia's
Borderlands it will go back to Russia
okay and the western part of Ukraine
will go back to
to Poland Belarus or whatever we'll see
about that uh Slovakia Hungary maybe
that's what Putin is willing to do but
eventually Putin will decide the fate of
Ukraine it's going to be most likely at
some point in time in the future maybe
in the next five years perhaps most of
Ukraine will be reintegrated into Russia
that's what's going to happen I'm saying
this today let's see if I'm right or
wrong
okay carik says there are multiple
terrorist attacks how are we going to
tackle this with reference to Parliament
attack and the JMK attack on the Indian
army look multiple fronts are being
opened up against India in anticipation
of the 2024 general elections the
objective is to create chaos in India
and to make the current government look
weak just before the
elections and who is doing all
this okay okay you think it's Pakistan
who is doing
this you think it is some random group
of primitive Savages who occupy parts of
Manipur who do
this who is coordinating all this who is
giving the leadership you think a bunch
of primitive tribals have the intellect
and the leadership to to carry out a
sustained coordinated campaign in
Manipur you think these terrorist are
just randomly coming in through through
the Lo in Jammu and Kashmir it is all
being done in a coordinated fashion
okay and we can actually expect more of
this the parliament attack also whatever
there was
yeah so how are we going to tackle this
right now India has two choices we wait
for the election to get over we play
defense we play defense we play defense
for the next six months
and we may have to absorb and swallow
some pain in the process but you
know you always have to think about the
long term you don't think of the short
term sometimes you have to absorb some
pain in the short term and I think some
people will not like what I say but
that's simply the way the world works
you to prioritize your long-term
National interest so I think that's what
the government is doing right now we
will for the time being
absorb we'll play defense for now we may
absorb some play pain if the pakistanis
cross certain lines when it comes to
these terrorist attacks we may retaliate
and uh
disproportionately but that remains to
be seen what lines the pakistanis are
willing to
cross uh so my point is this is all
being orchestrated orchestrated not from
India's neighborhood but from Far
outside of India from far away from
India's neighborhood okay there are
certain powers that don't want India to
rise there are certain powers let me
just say it aloud the United States
doesn't want a strong government to come
to power in India in
2024 and I'm just saying that they uh
that you can expect more of this to
happen before 2024 so right now there
are a number of options for India first
of all the simplest option is play
defense absorb some some pain for some
time after the election is done and
dusted we will take certain steps the
Hammer will fall on yeah you know who
East and West both sides the hammer will
fall
eventually where are you from why don't
you accept super chats I am from another
planet Epsilon idani why don't I accept
super chats because I want to give
everybody a Level Playing Field long ago
when I started this show the ask show I
had for some time for some episodes I
had accepted super chats and then I then
I realize that you know most of my
viewers are students and students are
broke I've been there I've been a
student students don't have money and if
I start
accepting money to answer questions it's
kind
of yeah I mean it's not that's not who I
am right and I want everybody to be able
to ask questions regardless of whether
they have money or not that's why I
don't accept super
chats
Kush sha says what's your opinion on
vivik ramaswami very interesting guy uh
Republicans typically Indians American
Indians are Democrats blindly supporting
the Democrat Democratic party but
ramaswami is a republican so is Nikki
Haley VI ramaswami is a super smart guy
who has the right answers for every
question who has the right arguments
that can destroy any opponent and very
interestingly he has consistently and
repeatedly and always refused to
criticize one person Donald Trump so I
think VI ramaswami is playing a
long-term game the actual Target is 2028
the 2028 election right now he will make
a name for himself and he is very
impressive and lots of people are slowly
coming around to support him in the
Republican party uh Republican voters I
mean you know people citizens who
identify as Republicans they are more
and more coming around towards
supporting him and having a very
favorable opinion of him he is taking a
very principled stand he's criticizing
his own party candidates like Nikki
Haley especially for being compromised
and corrupt and all that and he refuses
to criticize Donald Trump so the best
possible result for Vivic ramaswami in
the 2024 upcoming election is that he
Donald Trump accepts him as his vice
presidential candidate so for 202 before
VI ramaswami is not targeting a
presidential run he's hoping to be
Donald Trump's vice presidential
partner that's how I see it and he has a
bigger prize further down the line the
2028 election in which he would want to
run for president the top office that's
how I see it very smart guy and uh very
popular among the Republicans among the
Republican
voters
okay where are we what else do we have
we already answered the question about V
culture
um even Lord says do you think the US
will face martial law during the 2024
election cycle not sure about that
martial law I mean us is anyway an
autocratic Nation what did I just say
the US an autocracy yes it's an
autocracy do you know how easily you can
be shot shot in the US by
cops it's so easy to be shot by by cops
in the US it's it's anyway a nation
that's crawling with cops you take the
cops away from New York City for 15
minutes you're going to have riots just
15 minutes I promise you New York City
is crawling with cops everywhere you
take them away for 15 minutes you're
going to have riots it's a nation that
functions because of an overwhelming
police
presence it's already a nation under
martial law it's and everybody has guns
every what can I say
so will there be violence in the 24
election cycle I hope not of course I
hope not but who knows so
yeah depends on what steps the two
political parties
take
right kataria says any recommendations
for reading sources for a newbie
interested in world history in
geopolitics look if you want to
understand geopolitics you have to
understand history there's no way out
there's no textbook of geopolitics I
have not read a single book whose title
is
geopolitics there are no books on
geopolitics I will write one okay that's
down the line uh there are no books on
geopolitics so the the only way to
actually gain an understanding of
geopolitics which is how the world
really works the only way to do that is
to study a lot of history world history
local history and so on so forth so
there are no books on geopolitics that's
answer number one number two to stud to
really gain some kind of understanding
of geopolitics study a lot of world
history lots and lots and lots of it
because that's how you start
understanding the cause and effect chain
causality why do things happen how do
they happen what's there's a lot of
human psychology in there so what would
I recommend for world history I would
recommend will
durat will Durant let me put that out on
the thing where is the thing uh will
Durant
will the story of civilization I think
it's called a story of C
civilization
civilization let's create
that and let's put that there see that
that thing that's a multiple volume set
of books huge it'll take you maybe a
couple of years to read but yeah start
there it's not easy you got to do that
Anisha says hello sir hello
ma'am
um what
else F says how is antactica there in P
rise map 1513 did en people know more
about the world than you think possible
possible so I don't have the map with me
right now but yes there's a map from
1513 like the just says uh in case that
year is correct but yeah yeah there's an
ancient map that shows Antarctica or or
some kind of landmass where Antarctica
actually
exists so what does it mean well the
simplest explanation is that somebody in
that during those days the 16 Century
actually knew that there was this
continent called Antarctica and why is
it so hard to believe people travel
people want to explore uh New Horizons
they want to go where nobody else is
going before that's one of the driving
forces of human nature not all of us has
that not all of us not all of us have
that but some of us have that desire
that that uh the driving force that let
me go and do something that nobody else
has done and such people risk a lot so
yeah it's possible that somebody in
Europe knew about this and that's why it
is there on the map I mean why else
would a land mass be placed on a map
exactly where tactica is so it's
possible it's
possible
okay ba says have you watched avatar the
Last air bender in the legend of kurra
why don't we see any such animations on
Indian history the creators of the
series nicely combine East and West
Concepts I haven't seen the last air
bender I haven't seen the legend of Kora
I have I don't have the time to
watch I I mean I I love movies I love uh
TV series as a kid I used to watch a lot
of cartoons anime whatever uh but I
haven't seen any of these no time
unfortunately but I know that they are
really well done very well designed very
well uh narrated very interesting
engrossing stories and they combine this
East and West thing mainly Japanese
enemy with some blend of Japanese
culture with western western elements
and all that Concepts and all that and
the Japanese you know they they they
they had that anime version of the
ramayan beautifully made better than
anything Indians have made so I don't
know so why do we not see such
animations on Indian history because
nobody's bothering to do it it takes
time and money to do it and all and
whoever is the time and the money is
isn't very fond of Indian culture
look who is creating
content in India from an entertainment
perspective I'm not talking about people
on YouTube I'm talking about the actual
industry it's Bollywood isn't it and the
various OT platforms which put out
various OT series and all that I don't
watch any of those because the quality
is mostly mostly AB abysmal some of them
may be good but I I don't
bother so look you give me $10
million okay I'm going to make it get it
done you need money to do that you see
you need money to do it so the money is
in the wrong people's hands and the
people who who are interested in this
they probably don't have the money or
they don't have the KN how and the
wherewithal to do this so I think as
India becomes more prosperous as the
Indian economy grows you will see more
of this coming out I would love to see a
a 10
season uh a new animated version of the
Mahabharata and also the ramayan 10
seasons 10 episodes per season how about
that it'll be brilliant
animated I mean in animation you can
actually visualize the world as to as it
used to be if you are doing live action
you have you need to have costumes you
need to have props you need to have
locations it's very hard to bring out
the truth of the ancient reality of
India in animation you can do it so I
think I would love to see a 10
season uh new animated version of the
ramayan and the Mahabharat 10 episodes
per season total 100 episodes I would
love to see that you know because it's
such complex rich and detailed story The
Raman as well as the Mahabharat I'm not
saying story isn't story isn't Fiction
it's
history but it it's something that's so
complex and it it spans Generations
essentially the entire uh
literature so that would that would take
time to do I would love to see it I
would love to see it well done and
wellmade and respectful of Indian
culture I mean you know there are
there have there this there was this
movie recently uh I forget the name of
the movie in which Lord which was about
the
rayan uh who's that guy who plays raavan
sa Ali Khan or whatever I mean I could
not bring myself to go and watch the
movie okay so there are these atrocious
Stakes on the ramay in the Mahabharat
that Bollywood comes up with so yeah I
would love to see it happen you know
animated versions in the future
okay surj K says can NRC be the solution
to the Manipur crisis if not what else
can it be uh look the money look I
I I have an entire episode on Manipur I
also have a podcast with uh I have a
podcast Manipur as well in which I am
not the main speaker but I have an
episode of ask abijit about Manipur a
two hour episode but let me answer the
question look first first of all we to
understand to solve a problem you to
First understand how you have to
understand the nature of the problem to
understand the nature of the problem you
to look into the history of the problem
how was this problem
created Manipur right now what's the
situation in Manipur do we know where
Manipur is my dear Indian
friends okay let's find Manipur we know
where India is go to the Far East of
India which they call the Northeast and
here we have the state of Manipur it's a
state today it used to be a kingdom it
was a large Kingdom parts of tripura
were part of it much of nagaland was
part of it various parts of present day
Burma were part of the kingdom of
Manipur the kabo valley and and further
at some point in time Manipur King even
conquered parts of yunan presently China
okay and Manipur has a very ancient
history at least 2,000 minimum maybe
maybe three and a half thousand maybe
more and the manipuri language has ex
existed for 2,000 years at least and
which ethnic group speaks is the
originator of the manipuri language is
it the nagas the mes or the kookis it's
the mes so the true manipur's the true
natives the true indigenous people of
Manipur are the mes and the nagas the
nagas are essentially the same people as
as AES but they live in the in the Hills
long story now when did these foreign
infiltrators enter Manipur the process
began in the let's say in the middle of
the 19th century it all began with the
root cause of the problem is bad
succession once a king Dies who comes to
power next bad succession so bhaga
Chandra he was he he elevated manipuri
culture to to the High Heavens okay
whatever you see of manipuri culture
today whatever is left is much of it is
thanks to bandra King bandra but when he
died there was infighting between his
sons as to who becomes the king so he so
despite being a great patron of culture
bhandra messed up when it comes to
succession and that is that you cannot
do so because there was infighting
between his sons the burmes were able to
invade Manipur okay and there was the
seven years of Devastation after that
Manipur again regained her freedom but
the kings were weak and the British were
involved in the Treaty of yandabo and
that's how the foreign interference in
Manipur starts and the British became
the main power in the Kings became
essentially feeble and weak and that's
how and then the British started
started advising let's say the manipuri
king to bring in certain people from
from what is currently Burma these are
the so so very small numbers of these
people who were living in Burma were
brought in the so-call cookis okay it's
not one ethnic group it's a multitude
multitude of various tribes so the Third
cookies whatever um so the thing is this
that's when a very small number of these
infiltrators were brought in by the
British the British forced the manipuri
ging to do this but even in 1900 191 the
percentage of these cookies was less
than 1% in manip look at the British
records look it
up then more infiltration happened and
the mes fought a war against the British
for Independence in 1891 lost and as a
result the British punished them by
confining all the mes to the infal
valley region Which is less than 10% of
the entire region of Manipur today
present day region of Manipur and they
settled in these cookies these
foreigners into Southern Manipur Etc
where they exterminated the local Forest
people the Hill People the nagas all of
that where cookies live today it was
Naga territory all the nagas were
expelled from there violently
murderously so today the situation is
that the border is open okay it's long
story short and these people are just
infiltrating through the border of
Manipur and Burma and also VI missor
it's a whole different story there the
situation today is that half of Manipur
is under foreign occupation and these
these people are not even Burmese they
don't speak Burmese language the burmes
language they don't practice burmes
culture they actually are from Yan in
China okay originally go back like
three4 centuries that's the situation so
what is the solution the solution is to
expel all infiltrators of India first do
an NRC the NRC date should be
1949 1949 should be the NRC date anybody
who who who was not living in Manipur
before 1945 or whose parents or
Grandparents were not living in Manipur
before 1949 needs to go back to Burma
and then they Burma's problem you can't
have demog I I said earlier demograph
demographic change is a national
security
threat so that's what needs to happen
there is complete
lawlessness in more than half of Manipur
right now there have been horrific
atrocities
committed and I assure you that the
government of India is aware of
who um the perpetrators are who the
culprits are and when so this problem
will take minimum 20 years to solve we
know who the culprits are we know we
know who the terrorists are we know who
the infiltrators are and we know who the
victims are okay and the government also
knows when the hammer Falls it will fall
heavily but the problem will take
minimum 20 years to solve and the
problem between that the indigenous
people of Manipur face I'm talking about
the myth is zero leadership zero
cohesion you need to solve your own
problems first
okay you can't
expect
Outsiders I mean outside of Manipur to
come and solve all your problems the
problem was created by your king bhandra
because he did not choose the right
successor he did not make it clear to
everybody that who his choice of
successor was that's every downfall of a
kingdom or an Empire is because of wrong
succession and that's where the problem
began so Manipur has been in Decline
for the past 220 years it all began with
the death of of
bhandra and it's been a downhill slope
ever since and today the people of
Manipur the natives of Manipur the mes
are confined to about six or 7% of the
territory of Manipur and more and more
of their land is being taken over by
foreigners minimum 20 years to solve the
problem NRC is a good step but it has to
the cut off date should be 1949 so
that's what I can say about this in very
brief long long big thing but the
indigenous people of Manipur are the mes
and the nagas nobody
else
okay KV says what can India do for
protection at the Red Sea and Arabian
Sea so that we can trade without any
fear and what do you think of Middle
East Trade
Corridor look India needs to invest in a
very powerful navy we keep on saying our
we keep on let's say we we keep on
saying that the Indian Ocean region is
our strategic backyard yeah well you
don't own a backyard unless you have a
constant presence
there the rule number one rule of
territory is use it or lose
it okay the Chinese were able to take
over aiin by just walking into it and
building a road and India was not aware
if you're not Lo using the territory
you're going to lose it similarly in the
Indian Ocean region if we don't have a
major
Naval presence there at all times how
can we say it's our strategic backyard
words don't make it a strategic backyard
you got to take action so we need to
invest in numbers numbers of Naval
assets instead of investing in huge
gigantic aircraft carriers we need to
invest in smaller ships large number of
smaller ships that should be visible in
the Indian Ocean region in the Bay of
Bengal in the SE of sashtra in the lakad
sea and and south south of that
everywhere any one comes they should see
an Indian Naval presence everywhere they
should understand that now we have we
have come into India strategic backyard
and we see Indian Naval assets
everywhere that can only happen if we
invest in numbers quantity of ships
quantity of Naval
assets it doesn't have to be huge ships
it should be can be small ships missile
boats missile boats can be small but
they are they pack a deadly punch you
build a missile boat worth 20 or $30
million which is not a lot when it comes
to ships and you put three brahos
missiles on that it's a deadly deadly
asset to have and give it an endurance
of let's say 2,000 kilometers and 30
days or 60 days or whatever and then see
and build 200 of those it's not a lot of
money actually for considering the big
picture so India needs and India needs
submarines so what India needs to do is
that invest in large quantities of cheap
but effective Naval assets quantity as
well as quality some some of these
assets should be big like large warships
destroyers frigates Corvettes all that
but also smaller vessels as well large
number so every every time any anyone
enters this region the so-called uh
Arabian Sea the Bay of Bengal the ladep
sea wherever they should see the Indian
naal Presence at all times it should be
visible it should be in your face that's
when you know it's your strategic
backend that's when you have made it
your strategic backend otherwise the
Chinese will come over the Chinese are
already making in inrs in this region so
when so let's say the Chinese deploy 10
ships in this region but India has 200
ships here that's what we need to that's
the situation we need to make
happen so then India can trade without
fear and India can take care of all the
security issues in this region that's
what India needs to do India needs to
invest in a massive Navy it will take
time but we need to start and I think we
have started to some extent so I am not
entirely you know the level of
disappointment is is not that much I'm
actually kind of I find the situation
currently what we have currently kind of
encouraging a little bit not the way I
feel about the education system uh the
India middle east Europe trade Corridor
it's kind of a non-starter right now
because of the war in the Middle East
the Hamas Israel war um so let's see if
situ if the situation calms down in the
future we can start it but right now
it's it's non it's not started right
now
okay okay what is it what is it what
else do we
have shantan Singh says how do you see
the future of Hinduism as demographic
change is draining Hindu cultures
true I think whatever demographic change
we're talking about whatever else we are
seeing I think it's a temporary
thing our culture what we call Hindu ISM
has existed for 10,000 years at least I
don't see I mean yeah if you look at it
from a pessimistic perspective you may
say you may sometimes in your your
darkest moments feel that Hinduism won
last 100 years some people say that I am
by Nature not a pessimistic person I
think Hinduism or our culture it will
obviously evolve over time I think it'll
last at least another 10,000 years and I
think it will it will see a
resurgence in the next 50
years major
Resurgence okay and that is all going to
be tied in with India's economic and
Military rise and India's military rise
doesn't mean something that's hegemonic
in nature India has never been a
hegemonic civilization never okay uh so
India needs to become a powerful
military massively powerful military but
not for hegic purposes just to ensure
the status quo in the region and and uh
to ensure Justice in the Indian
subcontinent region and the overall
civilizational neighborhood I think it's
inevitable India needs to just take the
next 20 years very carefully ensure that
there's no major military conflict that
we are involved we are embroiled in if
you can navigate the next next 20 years
carefully and successfully no one can
stop us and with India's economic and
Military rise we will see a Resurgence
massive Resurgence in Indian culture
okay and those who and even our
neighbors close neighbors further
neighbors neither neither further apart
all of them will be strongly strongly
influenced by that and they'll be drawn
towards that again so it's going to
happen I am pretty sure of that I am
very optimistic and let's see how it
goes
okay okay what else do we have what else
do we have um
possibility of India us a war in the
future uh no no so the US even if it
wants to go even if it wants to go to
war with someone it doesn't get involved
directly first of all I don't see a
conflict between India and the US you
may have these diplomatic problems and
not sending Biden even though he had
accepted the Republic you know celebr
Republic Day celebration and all that
that's s of those tensions will persist
but the Americans I don't think even if
they want to go to war with India they
won't do it directly they'll use a proxy
they have a wonderful proxy right next
door to India Pakistan so why would they
go to war with India directly I mean for
decades the Americans financed and
funded Pakistani terrorism in
India so they won't do it directly there
will be no India us war in the future
okay India will make sure that we we
have reasonably good relations of course
the US sees India as a long-term threat
long-term like 20 year 50e Horizon and
they don't want India to rise we know
that very well we understand that very
well the India the US is not a long-term
wellwisher of India that is very clear
we have to understand that properly but
I don't see a war
happening but they certainly will use
proxies against India like they
currently
do like they currently do see the
situation J and right now new Spate of
infiltrations right from Pakistan
occupied
Kashmir well recently Asim the Pakistan
Army Chief was in the US like this week
why does he have to be go to the US he
met the the foreign the Secretary of St
State blinkin he met Victoria
newand okay nothing good can come out
come out of that the only utility that
Pakistan has for the US is as
counterweight to India
as a proxy to to hurt India with and
there's another proxy in the East the
the armed groups Rebel groups that are
fighting the burmes
government and they are also creating
havoc in Manipur and who supports the
antique burmes government Rebels well
guess who supports them the answer is
very clear so I don't see a war but they
will use all kinds of proxy forces
against
India all right
um yeah of course we we agree that's
that's a
major outcome that he would have wanted
Mr
aun rent smart why doesn't the current
Hindu government free Hindu temples oh
listen I don't know I mean I've always
said this that India is a Hindu phobic
apar state in which the indigenous
religion and culture of India is the
second is treated as second class or
like some would say eighth class
citizens and uh every foreign every
practitioner of a foreign religion has
the right to mind their own business do
things as they want run their own
religious institutions but the
indigenous culture of India is Shackled
and enslaved and all the
proceeds of the donations to Hindu
temples are are stolen by the government
and used for God knows what activities
so I think in certain States they have
done this but I think it needs to be
done Nationwide so until that happens we
are India is the world's most Hindu
phobic Nation okay that is true is
true all
right what else do we have let's see
okay we have cross two hours I'll take
maybe one or two questions maximum
and
um okay what is this not a simp should
India leave bricks it has become a
dictator's Hub with the possible in
integration of Saudi Arabia UAE and Iran
is there any possibility of Pakistan
joining bricks okay look at bricks
Brazil India China South Africa and
Russia apart from China Brazil we have
good relations with them Russia more
than good relations South Africa good
relations nothing wrong with them I
don't care if a country has a dictator
or not how do I care as long as they
friendly with me I'm
happy Saudi Arabia dictatorship yes
monarchy monarchy is a dictatorship but
we have excellent relations with Saudi
Arabia so what's your
problem UA great relations with
India yeah they have a monarchy
dictatorship so what Iran good relations
with India not bad they have Islamic
rule dictatorship whatever so what my I
just don't understand why Indians are
emotional we don't look at the world
affairs from a national interest
perspective we look at the world from a
moralistic perspective oh they don't
have democracy so we should not be their
friends their dictator is a great friend
of India their dictator helps
us he interest align with my interest so
why should I not like him why do we have
to look at the from a moralistic
perspective there is no right or wrong
in geopolitics there is no morality in
geopolitics it's only about prioritizing
your National
interest look at the US they prop up
dictators all over the
world look at the number of dictators
they propped up over Africa look at the
number of people they've
assassinated in Africa because they went
against us interests the US itself is a
two-party state by the way and both
parties have the same foreign policy so
it's essentially a mono it's actually
nothing not very different from China
actually the US okay so how do I care if
a certain nation has a dictator or
whatever or a king or a queen or
whatever as long as they their interests
align with mine and they are friendly
towards me how do I care I think we
should be part of such organizations the
only issue is Pakistan joining bricks
which China may push through if that
happens then you know it's
great any organization any multilateral
organization that involves it has India
and Pakistan both as members is doomed
to fail look at
Sark so if they bring Pakistan into
bricks it's going to essentially
paralyze bricks okay so if they want to
kill bricks they should bring Pakistan
in that's how I see it but when it comes
to dictators I just don't get India the
the moralizing perspective of Indians oh
it's not right there is no democracy
what is democracy where do you have
democracy in the world you have
democracy in the US a two-party State
just one step above a one party system
like China and North Korea you call that
democracy both parties have the same
foreign policy one of them uses bombers
to flatten cities with black colored
bombers the other one uses rainbow
colored bombers to flatten cities but
they do the same
thing look beyond what the surface level
of
things so I think India India has
excellent relations with the
dictatorships in Saudi Arabia UAE Iran
Russia whatever you want to say and I'm
happy we have excellent relationships
with these dictatorial regimes because
it's good for India I don't care what
they do in their
country and it doesn't mean that
dictatorships are bad by the
way India for the longest time had an
imperial monarchy system who was Lord
Ram he was the king of India what is a
king a king is a dictator by the way
Singapore Lewan you he was a dictator
but he was a Great Dictator benevolent
dictator so please stop looking at the
world from a moralistic simplistic
sheeplike
perspective please evolve your
thinking all right all right I will take
one more question we have gone way
Beyond two
hours Anisha says CIA wants India to go
towards Tibet if China goes for Taiwan
is there a possibility of that uh I
don't know if CIA has said this
officially the Central Intelligence
Agency of the US they are the
troublemakers in the rest of the world
the FBI is the Troublemaker within the
US so
um I don't know if they have sent this
okay but if they want India to go
towards Tibet if China go towards Taiwan
my question is what is right for India
it is we in India who will decide it is
our government that decide what is best
for India eventually I think Tibet needs
to be free of course it needs to be free
I had this podcast with tenzen sundu in
which we disced discuss the entire Tibet
issue I would recommend you watch it uh
eventually we do want Tibet to regain
its
freedom Tibet has historically always
been free and it's G it's always been
the buffer between India and
China uh so we do want this to happen
but is this the right time let's say
China invades Taiwan in
2025 is 2025 the right time for India to
Red to to free Tibet that is a
calculation that has to be done based on
a number of factors the current strength
of the Indian
do we have expeditionary Warfare
capabilities far from India will we be
able to resupply the Troops if they
reach urumi or or Lassa or wherever can
we actually make inroads rapidly across
the ti Tibetan Plateau the mountain
Warfare issue what will China's response
be how will they be able to reinforce
the you know send supplies they only
have one rail line etc etc lots of
factors to take into consideration will
China be able to divert its military and
fight a war in Tibet lots of factors
okay so uh personally I'm not sure if
2024 2025 hypothetically if it's the
year of the invasion 51 I'm not sure if
it may be the right time for India to
make a move on Tibet Maybe not maybe yes
I don't know uh so and ideally we don't
want a war for the next 20 years ideally
Tibet is already like way it's been a
long time since it's been uh annexed by
China uh so another 20 years won't do it
too much harm ideally we don't want a
war for 20 years with anyone then nobody
will dare to go to war with us if we if
we grow our economy for for the next 20
years so that's how I see it all right
this is the end of today's session thank
you so much for all of your questions I
apologize once again to all of you whose
questions I could not take obviously you
have thousands of questions coming up
over year but yes we will keep on doing
this Asko this is the final episode of
this year next year I'm going to do way
more episodes than I've done this year I
may even do some surprise episodes
impromptu episodes possibly we'll see
how it goes all right so thank you so
much for your viewership for your
support I really appreciate it I wish
you all a great end of the year a great
year ahead and we will meet again and
and next year you will see much more of
me all right so take care have a great
time and uh keep raising your standards